Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Drama, Records SC0690
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Drama, records
1905-1995
bulk
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Department of Drama
SC0690
13.25 Linear Feet (18 boxes)
This collection includes production books from various plays put on by the department and one box of miscellaneous records including course bulletins, syllabi, departmental pamphlets, and "A Report on the Activities of the Department of Speech and Drama and the Stanford Players, 1939-42." Accession ARCH-2012-078 contains production programs, set designs, water colors, photographs, and copies of purchase orders relating to production.
Accession ARCH-2012-078: Materials are extremely fragile, as they were stored in steam tunnels beneath Memorial Hall for over 60 years.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The records were received by the Stanford University Archives via administrative transfers from the Department of Drama.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Provenance
Accession ARCH-2012-078: Contractors working in Memorial Hall in 2012 found two boxes of records in an unused steam tunnel under the building. These boxes were labeled “Stanford Players 1937 to 1948” and had clearly been stored there since 1948, or very soon thereafter. The two boxes were in poor condition at the time of discovery. Upon transfer to the Stanford University Archives in 2012, they were immediately sent to conservation, where they were frozen to arrest any further deterioration.
Description of the Collection
The collection includes production books from various plays put on by the department and one box of miscellaneous records including course bulletins, syllabi, departmental pamphlets, and "A Report on the Activities of the Department of Speech and Drama and the Stanford Players, 1939-42."
Accession ARCH-2012-078 contains production programs, set designs, water colors, photographs, and copies of purchase orders relating to production.
College and school drama; Stanford University. Department of Drama; Stanford University. Department of Speech and Drama; Stanford University. Department of Drama; Stanford Players.
- General Records, Series 1
  - Report on the KPIX (TV) series "People Places Politics" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Radio program, "American Town Meeting of the Air", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Speech and Drama Department Course Bulletins, 1925-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Course Syllabi, 1935-1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Department Pamphlets, 1953-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Department Pamphlets [including "Stylish Silhouettes, Selections from the Department of Drama's Collection of Historic Costume"], 1971-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, Press Releases, 1905-1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ten Year Plan, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Posters (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Drama Contest Announcements, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Graduate Study Announcements, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Summer Quarter Announcements, 1937-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Readings and Miscellaneous, 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Report of the Activities of the Drama and Speech Department, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Book, "A Report on the Activities of the Department of Speech and Drama and the Stanford Players", 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Book, (carbon copy) "A Report on the Activities of the Department of Speech and Drama and the Stanford Players", 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Production Books, Series 2
  - "The Bacchae," 1965, script (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Bacchae," publicity (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Bacchae," sound and lights (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Bacchae," miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Bald Soprano," script (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "The Zoo Story," script (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Bald Soprano" and "The Zoo Story," notes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Bedtime Story," script (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Bedtime Story," notes (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "The Critic," script, Act One (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Critic," script, Act Two (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "The Critic," script, Act Three (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "The Critic," notes (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "The Dock Brief," script (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "The Duchess of Malfi," script, Act One (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "The Duchess of Malfi," script, Act Two (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "The Duchess of Malfi," script, Act Three (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "The Duchess of Malfi," script, Act Four (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "The Duchess of Malfi," script, Act Five (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "The Duchess of Malfi," notes and publicity (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "The Dybbuk," 1960, script, Act One (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "The Dybbuk," script, Act Two (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Dybbuk," script, Act Three (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Dybbuk," notes (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "East Wall West Wall," 1962, script, Act One (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "East Wall West Wall," script, Act Two (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "East Wall West Wall," script, Act Three (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "East Wall West Wall," prompt book, Act One (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "East Wall West Wall," prompt book, Act Two (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "East Wall West Wall," prompt book, Act Three (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "East Wall West Wall," notes and publicity (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "End Game," script (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Hamlet," script, Act One (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Hamlet," script, Act Two and Three (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Hamlet," script, Act Four (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Hamlet," script, Act Five (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Hamlet," notes (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "The Hostage," 1963, script, Act One (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "The Hostage," script, Act Two (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "The Hostage," script, Act Three (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "The Hostage," notes (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "I Knock at the Door," 1959, script (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "I Knock at the Door," notes (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "Man is Man," script, Act One (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Man is Man," script, Act Two (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Man is Man," script, Act Three (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Man is Man," notes (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Macbeth," script (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Macbeth," notes (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Macbeth," lighting and stage direction (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Maskarade," program [Drama department/Black Performing Arts] (Box 13)
    Acquisition Information
    Previously classified in the Stanford University Publications and Ephemera Collection "4digit" collection.
  - "The Matchmaker," script 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "The Matchmaker," script 2, Acts One and Two (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "The Matchmaker," script 2, Acts Three and Four (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "The Matchmaker," script 2, notes and publicity (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Measure for Measure," script, Act One (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Measure for Measure," script, Act Two (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Measure for Measure," script, Act Three (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Measure for Measure," script, Act Four (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Measure for Measure," script, Act Five (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Measure for Measure," notes (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "The Man Besieged," script, Act One (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "The Man Besieged," script, Act Two (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "The Man Besieged," script, Prelude (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "The Man Besieged," notes (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "No Trifling with Love," 1963, script, Act One (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "No Trifling with Love," script, Act Two (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "No Trifling with Love," script, Act Three (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "No Trifling with Love," notes (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - "One Can't Think of Everything," script and notes (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - "Richard II," script, Act One (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Richard II," script, Act Two (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Richard II," script, Act Three (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Richard II," script, Act Four (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Richard II," script, Act Five (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Richard II," notes (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "The Possessed," script, Act One (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "The Possessed," script, Act Two and Three (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "The Possessed," script, Act Four (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "The Possessed," notes (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "The Sea Gull," script (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "The Sea Gull," notes (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Six Characters in Search of an Author," 1962, script, Act One (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "Six Characters in Search of an Author," script, Act Two (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Six Characters in Search of an Author," script, Act Three (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "Six Characters in Search of an Author," notes (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Stage Door," script, Act One (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Stage Door," script, Act Two (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Stage Door," script, Act Three (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Stage Door," notes (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Stage Door," costume design (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Three Penny Opera," 1963-64, script, Prologue (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Three Penny Opera," script, Act One (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Three Penny Opera," script, Act Two (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Three Penny Opera," script, Act Three (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Three Penny Opera," notes (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Suddenly Last Summer," script, Scene One (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Suddenly Last Summer," script, Scenes Two and Three (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Suddenly Last Summer," script, Scene Four, 1 of 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Suddenly Last Summer," script, Scene Four, 2 of 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Suddenly Last Summer," notes (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "The Snob," script, Act One (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "The Snob," script, Acts Two and Three (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "The Snob," notes (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Tartuffe," script, Acts One and Two (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Tartuffe," script, Acts Three, Four, and Five (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "Tartuffe," notes (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "The Three Cuckolds," 1962, script, Act One (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "The Three Cuckolds," script, Act Two (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "The Three Cuckolds," notes (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Time Remembered," script Act One (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Time Remembered," script Act Two (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Time Remembered," notes (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Tinkle," Scene One (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Tinkle," Scene Two (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "A Touch of the Poet," 1960, script, Act One (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "A Touch of the Poet," script, Act Two (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "A Touch of the Poet," script, Act Three (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "A Touch of the Poet," script, Act Four (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "A Touch of the Poet," notes (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Turnadot," script, Act One (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Turnadot," script, Act Two (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Turnadot," script, Act Three (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Turnadot," script, Act Four (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Turnadot," script, Act Five (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Turnadot," notes (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Two Gentlemen from Verona," script (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Two Gentlemen from Verona," notes (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Under Milk Wood," script 1, Part One (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Under Milk Wood," script 1, Part Two (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Under Milk Wood," script 2 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "Under Milk Wood," notes (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "The Woman of Paris," script 1, Act One (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "The Woman of Paris," script 1, Act Two (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "The Woman of Paris," script 1, Act Three (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "The Woman of Paris," script 2 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "The Atom Clock," script (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - "Stranger at the Elizabethan Play," script (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Oversized materials removed from earlier boxes (Box 12)
- The Stanford Dance Division Presents...10 Years of Student and Faculty Works, 1995; Accession ARCH-2012-086; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2012-078
  - "A Comedy of Errors", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Alchemists", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Trojan Women", 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Uncle Tom's Cabin", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Johnny Johnson", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Winter's Tale", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Tobias & The Angel", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Nursery Maid of Heaven" and "Caleb Stone's Death Watch", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "King Lady", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Murder & Trial", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Star Wagon", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Gringo's Gamble", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Camille in Roaring Camp", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "The Mask and the Face", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Tovarich", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Hippolytus", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "No More Peace", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "The Two Shepherds", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "The Vikings at Hedgeland", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "A Knight's Landing", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "The Tempest", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Night Before the Border", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "She Stoops to Conquer", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Mr. Congressman", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "St. Joan", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Of Thee I Sing", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "The Wild Duck", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "The Poor of New York", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "Richard II", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Where the Dear Antelope Play", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Where the Dear Antelope Play", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Thunder Rock", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Knickerbocker Holiday", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Marco Millions", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Rain from Heaven", 1941 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Spring Shows, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Beggar's Opera", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "The Wookey", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Tartuffe", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "The Eve of St. Mark", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "The Wind and the Rain", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Charley's Aunt", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Little Theatre - One Acts: "A Happy Journey," "Hello Out There," and "A Village Wooing.", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Tonight at 8:30", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Moor Born", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "Moor Born", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Squaring the Circle", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "Do-Re-Mi", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "In Time to Come...", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "The Gondoliers", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Young Man of Today", 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Papa is All" (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "The Truth About Blayds", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Dover Road", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Is Life Worth Living?", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "School for Husbands", 1944 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "A Highland Fling", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Show-Off", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "The Importance of Being Earnest", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "My Indian Family", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "The Seagull", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "The Little Foxes", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "The Merry Wives of Windsor", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Morning's At Seven", 1945 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Goat Song", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Arms and the Man", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "The Magic Flute", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - "The Taming of the Shrew", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "School for Scandal", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - "The Father", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - "High Tor", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "My Heart's in the Highlands" and "John Doe", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Richard III", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Gaieties, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Autumn "One Acts", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Lysistrata", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Ram's Head Spring Show, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "A Prayer in Galilee", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "The Royal Family", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "A Doll's House", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "The Adding Machine", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "The Adding Machine", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - "Devil's Disciple", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - "Devil's Disciple", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Der Freischütz", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "Der Freischütz", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Devil's Disciple", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Chekov: 4 One-Acts, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "John Gabriel Borkman", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "As You Like It", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "Der Freischütz", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "No Exit", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - "Royal Family", 1947 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - "Cyrano", 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - "Cyrano", 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "Orchesis", 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "Double Revolver", 1948 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "Peter Grimes", 1948 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "Jason", 1948 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Macbeth", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - "Othello", undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "Fumed Oak", undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "Happy Journey", undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "My Heart's in the Highlands" and John Doe", undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "My Heart's in the Highlands", undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "The Warrior's Husband", undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - "The Warrior's Husband", undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Oh Foolish Love", undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "The Knight of the Burning Pestle", undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Unlabeled Set Design, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Unit Set, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Material Invoice, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Maintenance Requisitions, circa 1938 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Maintenance, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Maintenance, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - General, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - General, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Unit Set, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Advisor Information, circa 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Petty Cash, circa 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Additional Material
  Provenance
  Materials in this series were previously classified in the Stanford University Publications and Ephemera Collection "4digit" collection.
  - Drama Department performance calendar brochure, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Philippos poster, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2017-176
  - Framed playbills - All's Well that Ends Well & A Night's Lodging, 1938 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2017-151
  - Notes from "Pie" (Director), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Dybbuk, by S. Ansky (script), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings re the Dybbuk, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Dybbuk - production notes, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Golem - script, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)